(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T23:11:35.534195",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
唸るぜ
I'm gonna roar...
血泥
Even covered in blood...
ついたって
...and mud,
守りたい
I want to protect you.
革命道中
Revolution is on the way,
だって
even then,
君に夢中
I'm crazy about you.
暗闇
In this world
染み込む世界で
soaked into darkness,
見つけた
I found...
センチメンタルな恋
...a sentimental love.
甘くぬかるんだ
Your sweet, muddy...
眼差し
...gaze...
変に
...troubled me...
色気あるから
...with its strange appeal,
困った
and I'm in trouble.
手を
I want to...
繋ぐ勇気
...summon the courage...
出したくて
...to hold your hand.
身の程
But I can't do it...
わきまえてちゃ
...if I keep knowing my place...
出来ないね
...all the time.
暗い
From the walls...
トンネルの壁
...of the dark tunnel,
したたり落ちる
secrets are...
秘密
...dripping down.
しめやかに
A heart solemnly...
高鳴る
...throbbing...
鼓動
...fast...
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even the curses and illnesses
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
嗚呼 唸らせて
Ah, let me roar
満ち足りたって守りたい
Even if I'm fully satisfied, I want to protect you
革命心中だって 君に夢中
Even in a revolutionary double suicide, I'm crazy about you
暗闇染み込む世界で見つけた
I found you in this world soaked in darkness
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
なりふり構わず側にいたい
I want to be by your side, no matter what it takes
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうよ
I find myself expecting things from clumsy you
しがみつけば消えそうな火に
If I cling to this fire that's about to fade out...
恋 of 爪立てて近づいていい？
Can I draw the claws of love and come closer?
身を任せだらけだって
Even if I completely surrender myself...
全て失ってもいい
...I don't mind losing everything
しめやかに高鳴る心
My heart beats quietly but intensely
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も君となら
If I'm with you, even curses and illnesses...
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I go wild around here?
嗚呼 泣き喚ぶ 絶句しちゃうまで
Ah, I'll cry out until I'm utterly speechless...
離れない
...and never let you go
革命心中だって 君に夢中
Even in a revolutionary double suicide, I'm crazy about you
揺蕩う旅の狭間で見つけた
I found you in the gap of a swaying journey
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
突き進むなら二人で
If we are to press forward, let's do it together
革命心中だって 夢に熱中
Even in a revolutionary double suicide, I'm obsessed with this dream
ダメダメ 待て待て
No, no! Wait, wait!
呪いも病も抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even the curses and illnesses
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
It's fine if I go wild around here, right?
怖くたって唸らせて
Even if I'm scared, let me roar
満ち足りたって守りたい
Even if I'm fully satisfied, I want to protect you
革命心中だって 君に夢中
Even in a revolutionary double suicide, I'm crazy about you
暗劇染み込む世界で見つけた
I found you in this world soaked in darkness
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
Catch the Moment
そっと 吐き出す ため息を吸い込んだ
I breathed back in the sigh I quietly let out
後悔は苦い味残して
Leaving behind the bitter taste of regret
いつも なんて？ 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why is it always like this? Unable to say the most important thing...
次の朝日が顔だしてる
...while the next morning sun begins to show its face
嫌になった運命を ナイフで切り刻んで
Carving up the fate I grew to hate with a knife...
もう一度
...once more...
やり直したらキミに出会えないかも
...if I started over, I might never have met you
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
It all begins the moment my voice resounds
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The limit of my life, as my heart counts down
叶えても
Even if they come true...
...even if they come true...
終わらない願い
...these wishes never end
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は
Running with sweat dripping, the world's second hand...
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
...will one day leave me behind as I stop
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ 僕を Catch the Moment
It's testing me, so I must catch the moment
一個 幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count a single piece of happiness...
変わっていく 未来に怯えてしまうけど規定
...I find myself frightened of the changing future, but...
愛情の種を大切に育てよう
...let's carefully nurture the seeds of love
分厚い雲もやがて突き破るかな
I wonder if we'll eventually break through those thick clouds
キミの声が響いた
Your voice resounded...
僕の全身を通って
...traveling through my whole body...
心臓のドアをノックしてる
...knocking on the door of my heart
「臆病」でも開けちゃうんだよ
Even if I'm a coward, I'll open it...
信じたいから
...because I want to believe
何にもないと思ったはずの足元に
At my feet, where I thought there was absolutely nothing...
いつか深く確かな...
...one day, a deep and certain...
確かな 根を生やす
I'll grow a certain root,
嵐の
even if
夜が来たとしても
a stormy night comes.
揺らいだりはしない
I will never waver.
何度でも
No matter how many times,
追いついたり 追い越したり
I keep catching up and passing you by.
キミがふいに分かんなくなって
Suddenly, I lose track of you,
息をした タイミングが
and just when our breathing
合うだけで 嬉しくなったりして
aligns, it makes me feel so happy.
集めた一秒を
If only I could turn this second
永遠にして...
we gathered into eternity,
行けるかな
I wonder if we can do it.
僕の声が響いた
The moment my voice resounded,
瞬間に始まる
everything started.
命のリミット
My heart is counting down
心臓がカウントしてる
the limit of my life.
叶えても 叶えても
Even if they are granted over and over,
終わらない願い
my wishes will never end.
汗をかいて走った
I ran drenched in sweat.
世界の秒針が
The second hand of the world
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
will one day leave behind the frozen me.
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ僕を
It's testing me,
Catch the Moment
逃がさないよ僕は Bird
I won't let it go,
この瞬間を掴め
I'll seize this moment!
Catch the Moment
こんばんドドドー！
Good evening, dododo~!
お誕生日を2回迎えることとなった、角巻わためです！
I am Tsunomaki Watame, who ended up celebrating her birthday twice!
本当は6月6日が誕生日なんですけど、諸々が多くて中断、そして延期になり...
My actual birthday was on June 6th, but due to various reasons, it was interrupted and postponed...
今日！『角巻わため生誕祭2026 アニソンナイトフィーバー2』、改めて開催させていただくことになりました！
And today! "Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Festival 2026: Anisong Night Fever 2" is finally being held!
超迅速に動いてくださった運営さんたち！
To the staff who moved incredibly fast,
そしてライブを観に来てくれている皆さん！本当にありがとうございます！
and to everyone who came to watch this live, thank you so much!
1曲目『革命デュアリズム』、2曲目『Catch the Moment』と観ていただいて分かった方もいらっしゃるかもしれないんですが、
Having watched the first song "Kakumei Dualism" and the second "Catch the Moment", some of you might have noticed...
前回のライブで放送した部分は、万が一のために録画を回してくださっていたので、
the parts broadcast during the previous live were recorded just in case,
そちらの6月6日のバキバキ生誕当日のパフォーマンスを観ていただいて、
so you were able to watch that high-energy performance from the actual birthday on June 6th.
それ以外のソロとMCは、改めてこれ以上ライブ延期にならないように、
As for the other solos and MC parts, to prevent any further postponements,
今回は事前に収録をさせていただきました！
we pre-recorded them this time!
なので、未来のリアルタイムの皆のコメントを予知しながらMCしたいなと思いますので、いっぱいコメントしてください！
So, I'll be doing this MC by predicting everyone's comments in real-time in the future, so please leave lots of comments!
うんうん、わかったよ。はい、はい、うん。
Yeah, yeah, I get it. Yes, yes, mhm.
あ、ありがとうね。「おめでとう」？ありがとう！見える、見えるぞー！
Ah, thank you! "Happy birthday"? Thanks! I can see them, I can see them!
あははは！
Ahahaha!
ありがとうございます！説明はここまで！
Thank you very much! That's it for the explanation!
ここからはいつものライブ！今日は生誕ライブなので、
From here on, it's the usual live show! Since today is my birthday live,
たくさんこのライブに向けて準備や練習を、本当にたくさんしてきました！
I did a whole lot of preparation and practice for this live show!
ぜひ最後まで楽しんで、そしていっぱいお祝いしてもらえると嬉しいです！
I hope you enjoy it until the very end and celebrate with me a lot!
本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Today's hashtag is this one!
6月6日と変わらず、『#角巻わため生誕祭2026』になりますので、たくさんスクショとか感想とかポストしてください！
Just like on June 6th, it will be "#TsunomakiWatameSeitansai2026", so please post lots of screenshots and thoughts!
目指せ、またトレンド1位！
Let's aim for trending #1 again!
あとでじっとり、ねっとり、わためも見に行きたいと思ってますので、よろしくお願いします！
I'll be checking them out thoroughly and closely later, so thank you in advance!
では！ここまで、ヴァルヴレイヴの『革命デュアリズム』、ソードアート・オンラインの『Catch the Moment』と歌わせていただいたんですが、 Bonaparte
Now then! So far, I sang Valvrave's "Kakumei Dualism" and Sword Art Online's "Catch the Moment",
アニメや原曲MVに関連している演出を入れ込んだりしている、ので、皆わかったかな？
I included some elements related to the anime and original MV. Did you all notice?
たぶんわためいととかわかったかな？ぜひ細かいところまで観てもらえると嬉しいです！
I bet Watamates noticed! I'd be happy if you look closely at the details!
ここからはゲストパートもあります！
From here on, we also have guest parts!
皆の好きなアニソンも出てくるかも？
Your favorite anime songs might also appear!
ということで、ゲストパート盛り上がっていきましょう！
So with that, let's get hyped for the guest parts!
割れた鏡の中
In the shattered mirror...
映る君の姿
...reflecting your figure.
泣いている 泣いている
You are crying, crying...
細い月をなぞる指
...your finger tracing the crescent moon.
誰を呼んでいるの
Who are you calling for...
消えた恋の背中
...at the back of a vanished love?
何度でも 何度でも
No matter how many times it takes...
君の窓を叩くから
...I will keep knocking on your window.
夜の加速度に
Pushed by the night's acceleration...
背中押されて
...and driven forward,
糸が切れる様に
like a thread about to break...
ただ、君を 君を強く
I just wanted to hold you, hold you tightly...
抱いてた
...and so I did.
アンバランスなKissを交わして
Exchanging an unbalanced kiss,
愛に近づけよ
let's get closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
Let your tears and your sad lies...
僕の心に
...within my heart...
眠れ
...fall asleep.
昨日へのMerry-go-round
Yesterday's merry-go-round...
君を運んでゆく
...carrying you away.
止めたくて 止めたくて
Wanting to stop it, wanting to stop it...
僕は鍵を探してる
...I'm searching for the key.
崩れ落ちそうな
Supporting the sky...
空を支えて
...that looks like it's about to collapse,
ひとり立ち尽くす
I stand all alone.
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be...
いたいよ
...by your side.
アンバランスなKissで書かれた
The scenario of the two...
ふたりのシナリオ
...written with an unbalanced kiss.
愛と呼ぶほど 強くなくても
Even if it's not strong enough to be called love,
君のすべてが
everything about you...
痛い
...hurts.
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be...
いたいよ
...by your side.
アンバランスなKissを交わして
Exchanging an unbalanced kiss,
愛に近づけよ
let's get closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
Let your tears and your sad lies...
僕の心に
...within my heart...
眠れ
...fall asleep.
君の心が僕を呼ぶまで
Until your heart calls out to me,
抱きしめあえる
until the day we can embrace each other...
日まで
...hold on.
長い髪なびかせて
With long hair fluttering...
悩ましげなボディ
...and a seductive body,
この都会をハイヒールで
stepping through this city in high heels.
飛び回れば Big money coming, yeah!
If I leap around, big money is coming, yeah!
摩天楼の足下
Beneath the skyscrapers,
時代錯誤の罠
there's an anachronistic trap.
血迷った 危ない奴らなら
If they are crazed, dangerous ones,
極楽へいかせちゃうわ
I'll send them straight to paradise!
大胆な私の業の中 どれでも
From any of my daring techniques,
スキなものをあげる
I'll give you whichever you prefer.
大胆な私の業のどれでも
Whichever of my bold moves,
スキなのをあげる
I'll let you choose the one you like.
Bye Bye Sadness. And find out
行き場のない
You have nowhere to go,
あなただから...
because you are a ghost...
Bye Bye Sadness. And find out
私が今
Right now, I will
見つけ出して...
find you...
Ghost Sweeper
吸印もいいけれど神通棍はどう？
Spirit seals are fine, but how about my divine staff?
わがままは 許さないわ
I won't tolerate your selfishness.
逃がせないの Big money coming, yeah!
I won't let you escape, big money coming, yeah!
コンシャスなドレスから
From body-conscious dresses,
ゴージャスなライフも
to a gorgeous lifestyle,
いつだって 後からついてくる
they always follow me.
それが私のスタイル
That is my style.
クールだと誰かがゆうけれど
Some might call me cool, but
必ず
I will always...
幸せをあげる
bring you happiness.
Bye Bye Sadness. And find out
行き場のない
You have nowhere to go,
あなただから...
because you are a ghost...
Bye Bye Sadness. And find out
私が今
Right now, I will
見つけ出して...
find you...
Ghost Sweeper
Bye Bye Sadness. And find out
行き場のない
You have nowhere to go,
あなただから...
because you are a ghost...
Bye Bye Sadness. And find out
私が今
Right now, I will
見つけ出して...
find you...
Ghost Sweeper
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
your soul?
「もういっそ折れたままで」
"I'd rather leave it broken"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
I'm not so weak that I'd throw it away
強くないよ ほら
or run away, you see?
もう一度 鼓動 高鳴る
Once again, my heartbeat rises,
何が正しいかなんて
and although I don't know
わからないけど
what is truly right...
形のないものばかりが
The things that have no shape
大切になって行く
are the ones that become precious.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are strongly tied together.
また躓いて 転がって
Stumbling and rolling over again,
それでも砕けない
yet we still won't break.
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
your soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって
Just getting hurt and acting tough,
それでも見つけたいよ
yet I still want to find it.
魂のカタチ
The shape of the soul,
確かめてるよ
I am making sure of it.
深い地の底で一人
Alone at the bottom of the deep ground,
扉と鍵を探す
searching for the door and the key.
おとぎ話は ほら
Look, the fairy tale has...
泡の様に全部消えて
completely vanished like bubbles,
葛藤 残像だけ
leaving only conflict and afterimages...
次のページへ
as we move to the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
The growing branches split apart,
それぞれの道を行く
and each goes its separate way.
寂しい 思い出だけが
Only lonely memories...
強く 根を張ってる
...have taken deep root.
まだ貫いて失って それでも挫けない
Still carrying through, losing along the way, but never giving up.
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is my heart? Where is its vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Simply left behind and slipping away, yet I still want to tell you.
魂の日々を
The days of my soul,
魂の意志を
the will of my soul,
ずっと
forever.
Wow...
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the color of the soul?
赤色ですか
Is it red...
青色ですか
...or is it blue?
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the color of the soul?
透明な過去に
In a transparent past,
不透明な明日に
and an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは
you who live on,
何色ですか
what color are you?
また躓いて転がって
Stumbling and rolling again,
それでも砕けない
yet still unbroken.
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the color of the soul?
ただ傷ついて強がって
Just getting hurt and acting tough,
それでも見つけたいよ
yet still wanting to find it.
魂のカタチ
The shape of the soul...
確めてるよ
...I'm searching for it...
ずっと
...forever.
Wow...
イェーイ！
Yay!
3曲連続でお届けしましたが！
We just performed three songs in a row!
みんな、楽しんでますかー？
Is everyone having fun?
快適に見れてますかー？
Are you able to watch comfortably?
いやー、「アンバランスなKissをして」は
Yeah, for "Unbalance na Kiss wo Shite"...
月をね、写してもらったり
...we had the moon projected,
戦闘シーンをイメージして、炎に囲まれていたり！
and for the combat scene imagery, we were surrounded by flames!
ダンスの振りにもね、キャラクターの技が入っていたりしておりまして
Even in the dance choreography, we incorporated the characters' moves,
『ゴーストスイーパー美神』の『GHOST SWEEPER』にも
and even for "GHOST SWEEPER" from "Ghost Sweeper Mikami"...
お札をね、持っている振りが、あったり
...there was choreography of holding paper charms,
あとは幽霊が飛んでいる、そんな演出があったりしました！気づいたかな？
and we also had effects like ghosts flying around! Did you notice?
そして、『ソードアート・オンライン』の「ANIMA」は、いつか歌いたいと思っていた曲で
Also, "ANIMA" from "Sword Art Online" is a song I've wanted to sing for a long time,
満を持しての披露だったんですが、いかがだったでしょうかー？
so this was a highly anticipated performance. How did you like it?
いやー、かっこよかったなー！
Man, that was so cool!
すごいな、わためバキバキだな！あははは！
Amazing, Watame is so sharp! Hahaha!
では！まだこれで終わりではありません！
But! This is not the end yet!
ここからは、鏡...「鏡」ゲートを使ったギミックや、やってみたかった演出なども入ってくるので
From here on, we'll have gimmicks using the "mirror" gates and other effects I've wanted to try,
さらに盛り上がる、バチバチのセトリをいっぱいやっていきたいと思います！
so we're going to keep performing an exciting, high-energy setlist!
それでは、行ってきまーす！
Well then, here I go!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
An invincible smile ravaging the media,
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
wanting to know those secrets, so mysterious.
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her clumsy sides are part of her charm.
完璧で嘘つきな君は
So perfect and such a liar, you are...
天才的なアイドル様
...a genius idol!
今日何食べた？
What did you eat today?
好きな本は？
What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
If you go out to play, where do you go?
何も食べてない
I haven't eaten anything.
それは内緒
That's a secret.
何をきかれてものらりくらり
No matter what you ask, you dodge the question.
そう淡々と
So nonchalantly,
だけど燦々と
yet so brilliantly.
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
Secrets that seem visible but aren't taste like honey.
あれもないないない
Not that, not that, not that.
これもないないない
Not this, not this, not this.
好きなタイプは？
What's your type?
相手は？
Who is it?
さあ答えて
Come on, answer me!
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ」
"I don't really know what it's like to fall in love with someone."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Whether it's a lie or the truth, there's no way to know.
そんな言葉に
With such words,
また一人堕ちる
once again, someone else falls for you.
また好きにさせる
You make them fall in love again.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone gets their eyes stolen away.
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You are perfect, the most ultimate idol!
金輪際現れない
Unrivaled, you will never appear again.
一番星の生まれ変わり
The rebirth of the brightest star.
Ah
その笑顔で愛してるで
Using that smiling face with "I love you,"
誰も彼も虜にしていく
you lure and captivate everybody.
その瞳がその言葉が
Even if those eyes, those words,
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
are lies, that is a perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Right, right, that girl is special.
我々は端からおまけです
We are just extras from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
Serving as support role B to her star.
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
There's no way everything is thanks to her.
しゃらくさい 妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
How cheeky! How could we not feel jealous?
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This is no joke, that's why it's unforgivable.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない 自分を許せない
Imperfections are unforgivable! I can't forgive myself!
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't accept anyone but you, the strongest!
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes and worships you.
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Indeed, the strongest, unrivaled idol!
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses can be found.
一番星を宿している
The brightest star resides within you.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You must never show any weaknesses.
知りたくないとこは見せずに
Without showing parts we don't want to know,
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
you have to be one and only, no other way!
それこそ本物のアイ
That is the real love.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Stirring up the media with your specialty smile.
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
Keeping this secret completely hidden.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
Building a career on the lie of "I love you."
これこそ私なりの愛だ
This is my own way of showing love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the flowing sweat is beautiful aqua.
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
These eyelids that hid a ruby.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
I, who sing and dance, am Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lying is the ultimate form of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
I've never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
nor have I ever loved anyone before.
そんな私の嘘が
I believe that one day,
いつか本当になること
my lies will become reality...
信じてる
I believe it.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
One day, I will surely get everything.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Yes, I am a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのこと
Because I want to love everyone
ちゃんと愛したいから
properly with all my heart,
今日も嘘をつくの
I tell lies again today.
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
Wishing for the day these words come true.
それでもまだ
Even so, still,
君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
I couldn't say it to only you and you,
あ、やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it.
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is absolutely not a lie.
愛してる
I love you!
あいうえお菓子した
a b c d everything so sweet
かきくけこんなにも
f g h i just here for me
さしすせソフトクリーム
k l m n oh, so much ice cream
五臓六腑でいこう
that's what my four humors tell me
タッチついてトルテ来た
and after baking, a torte arrived
なにぬねのり塩
with seaweed salt on top
はっ！ひふへホットパイと
hot pie together with everyone
みんなでぬくぬく
to keep us cozy and warm
ショートケーキふわり
light and fluffy shortcake
キャンディーペロペロ
plenty of candy to lick
チョコレートの川で
sitting by a river of chocolate
綿菓子雲見た
I gazed at cotton candy clouds
アイスクリームと
ice cream and
プリンのお城で
pudding at a castle
カスタード渡狸
custard Watanuki
二人のランデブー
the rendezvous for two
パフェ色サンデー
parfait-colored sundae
あんこもハッピー
sweet beans to make us happy
たい焼きにクリーム
taiyaki and cream
小悪魔ドロップ
feisty little lemon drops
カップケーキから
from cupcakes
苺あんみつまで
to strawberry jam
国境なきsweets
this boundless kingdom of sweets
仲良くなれるよ
will bring us closer together
ぼんやり夢見てごらん
gaze into space and dream a little
キャラメルみたいにくっつこう
let's stick together in a sweet caramel pile
まみむめモンブラン
tasty mont blanc
やいゆえヨーグルト
and yogurt
らりるれロールケーキ
eat up a roll cake
渡狸とKissを
and a kiss for Watanuki
あいうえお菓子した
a b c d everything so sweet
かきくけこんなにも
f g h i just here for me
さしすせソフトクリーム
k l m n oh, so much ice cream
五臓六腑でいこう
that's what my four humors tell me
のんびり早弁
having a relaxed early lunch
焼きのりあぶって
eating toasted seaweed
おにぎりコロコロ
there's rolling onigiri
友達ほかほか
friends are so very warm
紅葉まんじゅうと
with some autumn maple manju
あんぱんお月さま
and sweet bean bread moon
渡狸に始まり
starting with Watanuki
渡狸に終わる日々
ending every day with Watanuki
ほんのり見つめてごらん
let's gaze gently at each other
甘くて苦い夕焼けを
at the bittersweet setting sun
タッチついてトルテ来た
after baking, a torte arrived
なにぬねのり塩
with seaweed salt on top
はっ！ひふへホットパイと
hot pie together with everyone
みんなでぬくぬく
to keep us cozy and warm
まみむめモンブラン
tasty mont blanc
やいゆえヨーグルト
and yogurt
らりるれロールケーキ
eat up a roll cake
渡狸とキッスを
and a kiss for Watanuki.
ミルフィーユ ワッフル ボンボン
Mille-feuille, waffle, bonbon,
ムース 渡狸 パイ
mousse, Watanuki, pie,
シュークリーム バナナゼリー
cream puff, banana jelly,
ババロア 渡狸
bavarois, Watanuki,
ホットケーキ バウムクーヘン
pancakes, Baumkuchen,
渡狸 ワタヌキ
Watanuki, Watanuki,
バター 渡狸 クレープ
butter, Watanuki, crepe,
ワタヌキ 渡狸
Watanuki, Watanuki.
ワタヌキとごはん
Watanuki and meals!
ワタヌキとおやつ
Watanuki and snacks!
ワタヌキと肉まん
Watanuki and pork buns!
ワタヌキと北京ダック
Watanuki and Peking duck!
みつまめ渡狸
Mitsumame Watanuki!
渡狸シロップ
Watanuki syrup!
金時渡狸
Kintoki Watanuki!
大盛り渡狸丼
An extra-large Watanuki bowl!
こんがり思い出色
Toasty, golden-brown memory-colored...
ハチミツみたいにとろける
...melting like honey.
あいうえお菓子した
A-B-C-D, everything so sweet,
かきくけこんなにも
F-G-H-I, just here for me.
さしすせソフトクリーム
K-L-M-N, oh, so much soft serve,
五臓六腑でいこう
that's what my four humors tell me.
タッチついてトルテ来た
Tag! Here comes the torte,
何？ヌネのり塩
what? Seaweed and salt.
はっ！ひふへホットパイと
Ha! P-Q-R-S-T, toasty pot pie,
ふたりでぬくぬく
keeping both of us warm and cozy.
まみむめモンブラン
P-Q-R-S-T, tasty mont blanc,
やいゆえヨーグルト
U-V-W-X, yogurt,
らりるれロールケーキ
A-B-C-D, eat up a swiss roll,
渡狸とキッスを
and a kiss for Watanuki.
ワタヌキの甘みと
Watanuki's sweet side, I love it,
ワタヌキの苦味
Watanuki's bitter side,
ワタヌキの酸味で
Watanuki's sour side,
好き好きラブ・コンボ
we love each other, love combo!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to the Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
うー！がぉー！
Grrr, roar!
高らかに笑い笑えば フレンズ
Laugh together and be friends, friends!
喧爪して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても仲良し
Even if we fight and become uncontrollable, we are best friends!
けものは居ても
There are animals,
のけものは居ない
but there are no pariahs.
本当の愛はここにある
The true love is here.
ほら 君も手をつないで大冒険
Here, let's go on an adventure with you, too.
ワン・ツー・スリー
One, two, three!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to the Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色
There are different appearances and shapes for everyone,
だから魅かれ合うの
so we get attracted to each other.
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When I soak my fingers into the setting sun,
はじめまして
Nice to meet you,
nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you.
うー！がぉー！
Grrr, roar!
振り向けば あちらこちらでトラブル
Look back and everywhere I see, there are troubles, troubles!
トラブル
Troubles!
なんてこった てんでんばらばら ちんぷんかんぷん まとまんない
What the heck, bang holler guffaw, it doesn't get settled!
けものですもの 大目に見ててね
We are animals, so forgive us.
みんな自由に生きている
Everyone is living freely,
そう 君も飾らなくたって大丈夫
yes, you don't have to maintain your image.
はい、どうぞ
Here we go!
Nice to meet you ジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you in the Japari Park!
今日からはどうぞよろしくね
I'm so glad to meet you.
いつもいつでも優しい笑顔
Smiling tenderly anytime, anywhere,
君を待っていたの
we were waiting for you.
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら
The open gate, after talking a lot about our dreams,
どこまででも
Anywhere,
anywhere,
続いていく
continuing,
グレイトジャーニー
great journey!
東へ吼えろ
Oh, roar to the east!
西へ吼えろ
Roar to the west!
世界中に響け サファリメロディ
Sound the safari melody all over the world!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to the Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Let's rock and uproar today, too!
姿かたちも十人十色
There are different appearances and shapes for everyone,
だから魅かれ合うの
so we get attracted to each other.
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
When I soak my fingers into the setting sun,
はじめまして
Nice to meet you,
nice to meet you.
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know more about you.
うー！がぉー！
Grrr, roar!
ララララ ララララ
La-la-la-la, la-la-la-la...
Oh, Welcome to the
ジャパリパーク！
Japari Park!
ララララ ララララララ
La-la-la-la, la-la-la-la-la-la...
集まれ友達
Gather around, friends!
ララララ ララララ
La-la-la-la, la-la-la-la...
Oh, Welcome to the
ジャパリパーク！
Japari Park!
ララララ
La la la la...
ララララ ラララ
La la la la la la la...
素敵な旅立ち
A wonderful journey
ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to Japari Park!
Fire!
Fire! Fire! Fire!
Oh, oh, oh, oh...
Fire!
Fire! Fire! Fire!
Oh, oh, oh, oh...
Night of fire!
Fire!
Welcome to the broken low
Welcome to the famous disco live
Come on, lady, come and go
Come on, lady, get me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door
I'll open, speak my name now
Speak it if you know how
Fly to me
Get ready for the...
Night of fire
You've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire
Come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire
You've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire
Come over, over me
Come over, over the top
You'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my rocky show
Welcome to the fire of the night
Come on, baby, let it go
Come on, baby, let me stick you tight
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door
I'll open, speak my name now
Speak it if you know how
Fly to me
Get ready for the...
Night of fire
You've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire
Come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire
You've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire
Come over, over me
Come over, over the top
You'll have a night of fire
You've better, better stay
The prayer to play
Come over, over me
You've never been here
Night of fire
You've better, better begin
Come over, over the top
You'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my rocky show
Welcome to the famous disco night
Welcome to my broken low
Welcome to the famous disco live
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it
Knock to my door
I'll open, speak my name now
Speak it if you know how fly to me
Get ready for the night of fire
Night of fire!
You'll have a night of fire
ということで！ここまでたくさんの、
And so! Up to here, many...
本当にたくさんのゲストさんたちと、歌って踊ってきましたが、いかがだったでしょうか！
really so many guests, we sang and danced together! How was it?!
楽しんでますかー！
Are you all having fun?!
なかなかね、こんなにホロメンが集まることってないのね、
You don't often see so many Holomem gather like this,
もう本当、生誕祭、お祭り！って感じで嬉しいです！
so it really feels like a birthday festival, a real festival! I'm so happy!
ゲストさんたちにも、大きな拍手をー！
A big round of applause for all the guests as well!
いや、ありがとう、みんなー！
Thank you so much, everyone!
ゲストのみんな、ありがとうー！
To all the guests, thank you!
いや、このね、鏡のモニターから登場するという演出をやってみたいなと思って、
So, I wanted to try this staging of appearing from the mirror monitors,
アイドルと、スイーツパレードで実現していただきました！
and we made it happen with "Idol" and "Sweets Parade"!
あの、わためいと、スバルさん、エルフレさん、るいさんたちが、
The Watamates, Subaru-san, Elfriends, and Lui-san...
ペンライトをね、振ってくれてたのも可愛かったし、
waving their penlights was also so cute!
やっぱり、ホロメンって可愛いよなー！
As expected, Holomembers are indeed super cute!
あと、ようこそジャパリパークへ、では、サバンナで肉食動物たちに囲まれて、
Also, in "Welcome to Japari Park", surrounded by carnivores in the savanna...
どのような人間がいたような気もしますが、
I felt like there was a certain human there,
みんながね、仲良くなっていく様子、表現させていただきました！
but we expressed how everyone became good friends!
ま、ちょっとね、最後みんなの表情怪しかったけどね。
Well, everyone's expressions at the end were a bit suspicious, though.
そして、ナイト・オブ・ファイヤー！
And "Night of Fire"!
これはもう、英語の上手なEN・IDメンバーのみんなと一緒に歌いたいと思って、
For this, I wanted to sing with the EN and ID members who are fluent in English,
横に立って歌っても浮かないように、英語頑張ったんだけど、大丈夫だったかな？海外ニキ！
and to not stand out awkwardly singing next to them, I worked really hard on my English. Was it okay, overseas bros?!
『英語上手！』『英語上手！』ってコメントが来てると思う！
I bet comments saying "Your English is great!" are coming in!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
でも、みんなもっと気になるところがね、あったかなと思うんですが、
But I think there might be another detail you guys are curious about...
あ、車ね！
Ah, the car, right!
攻めてたね！
That was pretty bold!
あとはパラパラを踊る、ギリわりロボね！
And the Giriwari Robo dancing Parapara!
やりたい放題させていただいて、とっても楽しかったです！
I got to do whatever I wanted, and it was so much fun!
でも、まだ終わりじゃない！
But it's not over yet!
ちょっと着替えてくるので、待っててくださーい！
I'm going to go change my outfit, so please wait for me!
よいしょ、よいしょ。よいしょ、よいしょ。
Yoisho, yoisho... Yoisho, yoisho...
着替えて、着替えて、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Changing, changing, yoisho, yoisho...
ふう。
Whew.
あ、もう着替え終わった。え、さて、次の曲なんですが、
Ah, I'm already done changing. Now, about the next song...
なんと！なんかみんな、もう知ってそうだけど、
What do you know! It seems you all might already know, but...
次の曲は新曲！『灰色の証明』をやります！
the next song is a brand-new song! I'll perform "Haiiro no Shoumei"!
わためチャンネルにて、MV公開中なので、MVもぜひ見てください！
The MV is currently out on Watame's channel, so please check it out as well!
そして、楽曲リリースもしているので、いいなと思ったらぜひ、買ってください！
Also, the song is officially released, so if you like it, please purchase it!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
では、新曲、『灰色の証明』、魂を込めて歌います。聴いてください。
Now, the new song, "Haiiro no Shoumei"... I'll sing it with all my soul. Please listen.
灰色の証明
Haiiro no Shoumei (Proof of Gray)
静寂に包まれた
Enveloped in silence,
ゼロ地点の感情を
my emotions at point zero,
期待を背負っているのは 私ではないから
for I am not the one carrying expectations.
主人公はいつだって 輝いている誰かで
The protagonist is always some shining someone else,
見上げるだけじゃ 何も変わらない
just looking up changes nothing.
今この時だけの 瞬間的な優位性で
With an instantaneous advantage that exists only in this moment...
駆け抜けて
...I will run through.
灰色の空を 裂いて
Tear open the gray sky!
私の全てを
Slamming all of my existence...
運命のシナリオに 叩きつけて打ち砕いて
...against the scenario of fate, breaking it to pieces!
自信は微塵もない
I don't have an ounce of confidence.
あるのは渇望だけ
All I have is longing.
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
I'll simply prove my own existence,
此処にいた事を刻むように
as if to engrave the proof that I was here.
綺麗な勝ち方は
A beautiful way to win
望むべくもない
is not even worth wishing for.
華やかさも必要ない
No need for flashiness either,
それが私だから
because that is who I am.
歴史はいつだって
History is always
勝者が作るモノ
written by the victors.
だけど記憶はその限りじゃない
But memories aren't limited by that.
今この時だけは
Only in this moment,
決断的な刹那性に
dive into this decisive instant,
飛び込んでいけ
and leap forward!
灰色の血で描く
Painting with ash-colored blood,
“私”の思いが
my desires
美しき痛みをも
will overcome even beautiful pain
乗り越えて書き換えていく
and rewrite it.
後悔は１ミリもない
There's not a single millimeter of regret.
あるのは灼熱だけ
There's only a burning passion,
ただ自分の生命を蹴り上げるように
as if kicking my own life into high gear.
始まりは些細 最早どうだっていい
The beginning was trivial; it no longer matters.
突き動かされ指先を伸ばす
Driven forward, I stretch out my fingertips.
現実は残酷だと気付いていないわけじゃない
It's not that I don't realize reality is cruel.
諦めるその時は“今”ではなかったらしい
The time to give up was apparently not 'now.'
灰色の空赤くもう一度点火して
Ignite the ash-colored sky into red once more,
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
and let me prove my own life.
そこにいた事を刻むように
As if engraving the fact that I was here.
はい！
All right!
ということで、新曲「灰色の証明」！
So, my new song, "Proof of Gray"!
やっと披露できた！やっと証明できた！
I finally got to perform it! I finally proved it!
聞いてくれて、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for listening!
この楽曲は、岸田教団＆THE明星ロケッツの
This song was created for me by Kishida Kyoudan
スポーツだったり、みんなが頑張りたい時に
with the hope of making an encouraging song that can
色々語ったら、かなり熱くて、かっこいい楽曲に
After discussing many ideas, it turned out to be
うまく行かないことがあっても、また立ち上がって
Even when things don't go well, rising up again
わためにとっても背中を押してくれる、そんな特別な
this live performance has made this special song
みんなにとってもそうだったら嬉しいです。
I hope it is the same for all of you.
こちらの新曲MVいっぱい見て、
Please watch the MV for this new song a lot,
楽曲もぜひ購入して、わための音楽を応援して
and I would be so happy if you bought the song to
目指せ、ソロライブ！
Aiming for a solo concert!
と、
And...
ここで、まだ告知していないものが一つありまして、
I have one more announcement that I haven't shared yet.
ライブじゃないんですけど、
It's not about a live concert, but...
なんと！
surprisingly...
じゃん！
Ta-da!
「角巻わためのHave a nice day」の
"Tsunomaki Watame's Have a Nice Day"...
書籍刊行が、決定！
will officially be published as a book!
ということで、「ハバナイ」が本になります！
So, "Habanai" is becoming a book!
出版社は「かいけつゾロリ」や「おしりたんてい」などで有名な
The publisher is Poplar Publishing, famous for
ポプラ社様より、オリジナルグッズ付きで12月に刊行予定です！
and it is scheduled to be released in December
まだ少し先にはなりますが、楽しみに待っててもらえると嬉しいです。
It's still a bit of a way off, but I hope you look forward to it.
そして、じゃん！
And next, ta-da!
今年も「角巻わため誕生日記念グッズ」が、
Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Commemorative Merchandise is also...
受注受付中、です！
now open for pre-orders!
ラインナップを改めて紹介させてください！
Let me introduce the line-up once again!
どどどど、どん！
Da-da-da-da, dum!
出た！ふーみママ描き下ろしの、
Here it is! Illustrated by Fumi-mama...
「わためのあったかブランケット」！
"Watame's Warm Blanket"!
なんと、セクシーです。
And it's actually quite sexy.
そして、裏面にはわためいとがいます！
Also, on the back, there are Watamates!
丸めるとね、わためいとの形になりますので、
If you roll it up, it takes the shape of a Watamate,
2wayでも使えます。ぜひ温もりを感じてください。
so you can use it in two ways. Please feel the warmth!
そして、どどどど、どん！
And next, da-da-da-da, dum!
「わため＆わためいと温感マグカップ」！
"Watame & Watamate Thermal Mug"!
こちらは、もた先生に描き下ろしていただきまして、
This was illustrated by Mota-sensei,
最初は夜の風景なんですけど、
and though it's a night scene at first,
温かいものを入れていただくと、その熱を感知して、
once you pour a hot drink, it senses the heat,
朝の景色に柄が変わるような仕様になっております！
and changes the design to a morning scene!
わための配信を意識してデザインしてもらったので、
It was designed with Watame's streams in mind,
配信を見ながらぜひ温かい飲み物を飲んでくださいね。
so please enjoy a warm drink while watching my streams.
そして、まだあります！
And there's still more!
どどどどどどどど、どん！
Da-da-da-da-da-da-da-da, dum!
「わためいとクッション」！
"Watamate Cushion"!
クッションとして使うもよし、飾るもよし、
Perfect to use as a cushion or for decoration,
とっても可愛いクッションなので、ぜひお部屋に
it's a super cute cushion, so please keep it in your room!
に置いてみてください！はい！
Please try placing it there! Yes!
最後に、どどどどどどどどどどどどん！
Lastly, dododododododon!
きた！わためなりきりアイマスク！
Here it is! Watame Cosplay Eye Mask!
眠っている顔と、わためと言えばこれ！の表情にしていただきました！
We have the sleeping face and, of course, this face!
果たして需要あるのか、気になる方はぜひ、なりきりアイマスク手に入れてください！
If you're curious to see if there's any demand, please get your hands on this cosplay eye mask!
こちらのグッズをフルセットで購入していただいた方には、どどどどどどどどどどどどん！
For those who purchase these goods as a full set, dododododododon!
わための直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと、つのまきわためのショートボイスセット15種類が特典としてついてきます！
A postcard with my autograph and message, plus a 15-type short voice set will be included!
今年も無制限で直筆を書かせていただく予定なので、ぜひこの機会にゲットしてみてください！
I'll be writing unlimited autographs again this year, so take this opportunity to get yours!
ということで、新曲MV公開中！楽曲リリース中！
And with that, my new song's MV is out! The song is now released!
誕生日グッズ発売中！12月、ノベライズ書籍刊行決定！
Birthday goods are on sale! And a novelization release is set for December!
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you so much!
このあとは、22時15分からメン限アンコールライブもありますので、よかったらメンバーに入っていただいて、引き続き楽しみましょう！
Up next, we have a members-only encore live at 22:15, so please join and let's keep having fun!
今年はなんと2days！お誕生日たくさんお祝いしてくれてありがとう！
This year was actually 2 days! Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです！
I was super happy!
それでは、メン限アンコールライブで会いましょう！まったねー！
See you at the members-only encore live! See ya!
静寂に包まれた ゼロ地点の感情で
In a ground-zero emotion wrapped in silence
期待を背負っているのは 私ではないから
Since I'm not the one carrying all the expectations
主人公は いつだって "輝いている誰か" で
The protagonist is always "someone who shines"
見上げる だけ じゃ 何 も 変わらない
Just looking up won't change anything
今 この 時 だけ の 瞬間 的 な 優位 性 で 駆け抜け て
Rush through with a momentary superiority that exists only now
灰色 の 空 裂い て
Tear through the grey sky
" 私 " の 全て を " 運命 の 物語 ( シナリオ ) " に 叩きつけ て 打ち砕け
Slam my everything against the "scenario of destiny" and smash it
自信 は 微塵 も ない ある の は 渇望 だけ
I don't have a shred of confidence; all I have is a craving
ただ 自分 の 生命 を 証明 しよう
I'll just prove my own existence
" 此処 " に いた事 を 刻む ように
As if engraving the fact that I was here
綺麗 な 勝ち 方 は 望むべくもない
A clean way of winning is not even to be hoped for
華やか さも 必要 ない それが " 私 " だから
No need for glamour, because that is "me"
歴史 は いつだって 勝者 が 作る モノ
History is always something created by the winners
だけど 記憶 は その 限り じゃない
But memory is not limited to that
今 この 時 だけ は 決断 的 な 刹那 性 に 飛び込ん で いけ
For this moment only, plunge into the decisive ephemerality
灰色 の 血 で 描く " 私 " の 思い が
My feelings drawn with grey blood
美しき 痛み を も 乗り越え て 書き換え ていく
Will overcome and rewrite even the beautiful pain
後悔 は 1 ミリ も ない ある の は 灼熱 だけ
Not a millimeter of regret, there is only burning heat
ただ 自分 の 生命 を 蹴り 上げる ように
Just like kicking up my own life
始まり は 些細 最初 どうだって いい
The beginning is trivial, it doesn't matter how at first
突き 動かさ れ 指先 を 伸ばす
Spurred on, I reach out my fingertips
これからも夢に向かって一緒に歩いて行こうね！
Let's keep walking together toward our dreams!
これからも夢に向かって一緒に歩いて行こうね